A Guide to the W. Dale Parker Papers, 1914-2006
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Series III. Writings and Speeches, 1952-2005
  - A Political Candidate's Guide - correspondence and marketing, 1995-1996, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - A Textbook Collection of 100 Inspirational Prose and Poetry, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - A Text Book Collection of 100 Inspirational Prose and Poetry - correspondence, 1990, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 2025: Life in the 21st Century: Geography 101: A Student Workbook, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 2025: Life in the 21st Century... - correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Your Personal Angel" drafts, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Your Personal Angel, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Your Personal Angel - addenda and correspondence, 1997-2003, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Around the Mountains and the World" (newspaper column), 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Camping Illustrated, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Personalities in the News" (newspaper column), 1964-1969, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Letters to the editor, 1974-2005, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "Appraising Performance and Developing People", 1959 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - "Thank You, Mr. President", 1974, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - "What Our Flag Means to Me", 1971, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "A Selection of Writings by Dr. W. Dale Parker", 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Essays and Opinions - general, 1967-2003, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - "Around the Mountains and the World" (newsletter), 1997 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "A Political Consultant's Congressional Newsletter", 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Essays and opinions - political, 1990-1999, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Essays and opinions - space, 1992, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - "My Home is Historic Virginia" - correspondence, 1989-1991, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - "My Home is Historic Virginia" (script by Bradley R. Mills, edited by Dale Parker) - first draft, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - "My Home is Historic Virginia" (script by Bradley R. Mills, edited by Dale Parker) - second draft, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Speeches and other public appearances - notes and drafts, 1955-1995, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Speeches and other public appearances, 1955-1973, n.d., [reel-to-reel audio recordings] (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Speeches and other public appearances, 1952-1995, n.d., [(audiocassette recordings] (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - "Prose and Poetry with Dale Parker" (radio show on WOIX-AM), 1983-1984, n.d., [(audiocassette recordings] (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Series IV. Jacquelyn S. Parker, 1967-2006
  - Awards and honors, 1979-2005, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Biographical sketches, 1989-1998, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1976-2006, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Greeting cards, 1990-1998, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Education and training, 1970-1981, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Legal documents, 1974-1990, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Mensa, 1983-1998, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Notes and ephemera, 1980-1994, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Public appearances and media coverage, 1989-1994, [videocassette] (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Public appearances and media coverage, 1979-1993, [(audiocassettes]; [2 items] (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Women Who Dared: American female test pilots, flight-test engineers, and astronauts, 1912-1996 (by Yvonne C. Pateman), 1997 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Printed material, 1967-1999, n.d., [2 folders] (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, 1974-2001, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Childhood scrapbook / photo album, 1973-1976, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook ("The Parkers, 1616-2006: Jackie"), 1967-2004, n.d., [3 folders] (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Series V. Space Program, 1962-2006
  - Project Gemini records, 1962-1965, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Reminiscences of space program and Parker Space Collections, 2000, [(audiocassettes]; [3 items] (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Personal correspondence, 1966-2006, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Fitzpatrick, Pat, 2000-2006, n.d., [2 folders] (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Mars, Charlie, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Morehead Planetarium commemorative medallion, 1974, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Museum of Flight, 2000-2001, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Organizations, 1989-[2001] (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - "Rendezvous in Space: a Tribute to Pete Conrad" - Museum of Flight, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Space Shuttle Challenger, 1988-1989, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Space Shuttle Columbia, 2003, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Space Walk of Fame, 1999-2006, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Space Walk of Fame oral history project (Dale Parker oral history), 2001-2003 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Memorabilia and ephemera, 1966-2006, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - From Malabar to the Moon: America's Early Space Days (by John A. Moeller), 2005 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Printed materials, 1965-2006, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Parker Space Collection - correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1973-2006, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Parker Space Collection - inventories, 1987-1999, [2 folders] (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Parker Space Collection - overview, 1985, [(videocassette recording]; [2 copies] (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Series VI. Politics and Politicians, 1956-2006
  - Benkie, Dee Dee, 2001-2005 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Biden, Joe, 1987-1995, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Boggs, J. Caleb, 1958-1973, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Bowles, Erskine, 1997-2003, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Burr, Richard, 1995-2006 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Bush, George H. W., 1973-1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bush, George W., 1992-2002, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Carter, Jimmy, 1976-1979, n.d., [3 folders] (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Chiles, Lawton, 1971-1995, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Clinton, Bill, 1991-2006, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Clinton, Hillary, 1993-2000 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Connally, John, 1975-1979 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Dukakis, Michael, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Edmisten, Rufus, 1988-1995 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Faircloth, Lauch, 1993-1995 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Fisher, Paul - The Plan / Center for Action, 1981-1992, n.d., [2 folders] (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Ford, Gerald, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Glenn, John, 1982-1990, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Gore, Al, 2000, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Graham, Bob, 1986-1994, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Gramm, Phil, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Gunter, Bill, 1985-1989, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Helms, Jesse, 1982-2003, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Hunt, James B., 1979-2003 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Kennedy, Ted, 1968-2006, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Kivett, Gary, 1998, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - McDowell, Harris B. Jr., 1956-1968, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Mondale, Walter, 1984, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Nelson, Bill, 1987-2006 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1961-1974, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Nunn, Sam, 1987-1991 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Quayle, Dan, 1990, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1984-2004, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Rove, Karl, 2000-2006 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Sanford, Terry, 1986-1992 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Stephanopoulos, George, 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Stone, Richard "Dick", 1977-1992, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Wallace, George, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Woods, Rose Mary, 1971-2005 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Personal correspondence (political) - outgoing, 1981-2005, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Personal correspondence (political) - incoming, 1957-2003, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Florida gubernatorial campaign, 1977-1978, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Democratic Party, 1957-1995, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Republican Party, 1990-2005, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Political memorabilia (presidential and vice-presidential tie pins and cufflinks), n.d. (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Political memorabilia (photos, printed material, and ephemera), 1945-1977, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Series VII. Business Enterprises, 1945-2005
  - Amy Carter peanut doll, 1977, n.d., [2 folders] (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Around the Mountains and the World (newspaper), 1986, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Multiple Services, Inc., 1960-1996, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Personal counseling service, 1967-1997, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Pictorial Gravesite Creations, 1989-1990, n.d., [2 folders] (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Political consulting, 1992-1996, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Space exploration and technology trivia game, 1985-1987, n.d., [4 folders] (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Sports medallions, 1974, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Other business ventures and employment, 1945-2005, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Series VIII. Pen Pals, 1993-2005
  - Pen pal project background, 1993-1994, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Afanevich, Alla, 1993-1994, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Amelchenko, Olga, 1993, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Other A surnames, 1993, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Bedunkevich, Vatslav, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Bochkaryov, Dmitri, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Boldina, Inna, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Borisova, Svetlana, 1993, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Bymakova, Luedmila, 1993, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Other B surnames, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Cherkes, Sergei, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Chopchits, Irina, 1993-1997, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - D-F surnames, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Gromenkov, Alexey, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Other G surnames, 1994, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Hodorovich, Olga, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Other H surnames, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Inshakov, Alexei (Alyosha), 1993-1995 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Ivanenko, Irina, 1993-2005, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Jurkova, Sergei, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Kalynovsky, Dima, 1993-1995, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Kolychev, Alexei, 1993-1997, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Kuzmin, Boris, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Kyselev, Pavel, 1993-1994, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Other K surnames, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Linkiewicz, Aleksander, 1994-1998, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Other L surnames, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Mihailow, Sergei, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Mishchenko, Andrei, 1993-1997, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Other M surnames, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Natalevich, Youry and Tanya, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Nevaykin, Dima, 1993-1994, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Nikolayevna, Inna, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Nikitin, I. V., n.d. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Okruzhnoj, Igor, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Olkhovskaya, Irina, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Osypenko, Elena, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Parkalova, Svetlana, 1993-2001, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Petroukhin, Nickolai, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Petroukhin, Valeri, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Pogorelov, Yvana, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Popov, Valery, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Prikhodko, Michael, 1993-1996, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Pyshko, Taisa, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Other P surnames, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Ruban, Igor, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Other R surnames, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Savchenko, Alexander, 1994, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Savchenko, Nickolai, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Savitski, Sergei, 1993-1994, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Sergeyeva, Irina, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Sivak, Raissa, 1994-1995, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Other S surnames, 1993-1995, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Taran, Vitaly, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Terentewa, Eugenia, 1994, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Trumpel, Tamara, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Tsyguliov, Alexey, 1993-1994, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Other T surnames, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Vasilyev, Anatoly, 1993-2001, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Vasyankin, Alexander, 1993-1994, n,.d. (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Vercherko, Dimitri, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Vlasenko, Veronica, 1993-1994, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Zalozhnev, Natasha, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Zaytseva, Olga, 1993-1994, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Zhuku, Yvana, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Other Z surnames, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Unidentified correspondents, 1993, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 49)
- Series IX. Mementos and Artifacts, 1943-2005
  - Mastodon tusk fragment, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Acropolis floor fragment, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Berlin Wall chip, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Chinese figurine, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Commemorative coins and pins, 1976, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Intel tie pin and cufflinks, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Dale Parker profile bust sculpted by Kyle Lusk, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Printed materials, photographs, and ephemera, 1940-2002, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - College of William and Mary letter sweater, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Series X. Photographs, 1910-1998
  - Photographs, 1910-1998, n.d., [4 folders] (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Photo album, ca. 1935-1990, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Photo album, ca. 1942-1981 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Photo album, 1943-1944, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Photo album, 1955-1985, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Photo album, 1960-1984, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Photo album, 1963-1984, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Photo album, 1965-1980, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Photo album, 1966-1972, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Photo album, 1974-1977, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Photo album, 1980, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Photo album, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Series XI. Scrapbooks, 1918-2004
  - "The Parker Family, 1616-2005" - vol. 1, Dale Parker, ca. 1918-2004, n.d., [48 folders] (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1922-1980, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1928-1951, n.d., [8 folders] (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1940-1974, n.d., [4 folders] (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1943-1977, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1954-1980, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook, 1979-1981, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Oversize Materials
  - Certificates, 1975-1996 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Otis Parker / Eva Dempsey marriage certificate, 1914 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "A Sky High Goal" (Orlando Sentinel Star supplement re: Jackie Parker), 1976 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Dale Parker gubernatorial campaign packet, [1978?] (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Carter/Mondale campaign bumper sticker, [1976?] (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified photograph, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1945-1957, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1955-1959, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1958-1960, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1)